# Balaji Shettigar

E-mail: balaji.shettigar@gmail.com

Mob: +91 9986177852, +97155 4309369



An IT Professional with all round managerial and technical expertise over 12 years of IT experience and over 10 years in to hotel IT Management with 4 successful pre-openings. Very capable with a proven ability to ensure the smooth running of hotel systems and to provide IT solutions and services that improves the efficiency and performance of a company. Extensive practical knowledge of hospitality system builds hardware and software network support, technical support and computer repairs

## **OVER VIEW**

Hands on experience in maintaining and working with hospitality management software's as listed.

Front office Software : PMS Opera

Restaurants POS : Micros 3700, 9700, Simphony

Accounting : SUN systems, Vision

Inventory control : FMC

Guest Management : GLS, Messagebox

Domain Control ADS: Windows 2003, 08, 12,16

MS Office package : 2010, 2013, 2016, 2019 including Mac systems,

Passport scanner /DTCM: Vicas, Samsotech

Email System : Exchange 2007, 2013, 2016, Google Apps and Office 365

HR & Payroll system: Paytrax, HR Net, Oasys

IP TV System : NEOS, Arantia, Televes, Samsung reach

IP Telephone : Avaya, Alcatel, NEC PABX System : option (11C meridian,

Door locks : Saflok, Hafele, Secure star and Ving card

Room Automation : Digivalet, Crave Backup systems : Symantec, Veritas

Firewall :Sonicwall, fortigate, Juniper HSIA - Ant labs : wired and wireless internet

Overall responsibilities included Purchase of IT hardware's, Servers, Systems, Printers, Scanners, Capex and Opex budgeting, Organizing/arranging and scheduling training, cabling implementation, testing and commissioning the property. Responsible for SLA and vendor negotiations. To Serve as duty manager on rotational basis.

## **PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Date of Birth : 24<sup>th</sup> September 1981

Visa status : Yet to obtain.

Marital Status : Married. (Dependents are Wife and 2 kids)

Languages : English, Hindi, Kannada, Tulu.

Typing speed : 35 words/p.m.

Driving License : UAE, Qatar and India.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

C Central Resort in Palm Jumeriah (5\* hotel managed by Central Hotels) Aug 2019 - July 2020. Role: IT Assistant /In charge of IT Department (Successful pre/ Soft and post opening) **203** suites (Hotel closed down till further notice due to Covid 19)

Centara Grand Hotel Doha- Qatar. (5\* hotel managed by Centara Thailand) Nov 2016– May 2017 Role: IT Manager (pre-opening property **357** suites)

(Hotel did not open and managing company pulled out due to Crisis)

Armani Hotel Dubai -Burj Khalifa (Dubai - 5\* hotel managed by Emaar) Feb 2015 – Oct 2016 Role: Assistant IT Manager (Operational hotel, **185** suites)

The Ajman Palace Hotel & Resort, (Ajman-UAE - 5\* hotel managed by HMH) Feb 2013 – Jan 2015 Role: IT Manager (Successful soft and post opening) **254** suites

3AG Network Solutions (Bangalore-India)

Jan 2012 – Feb 2013

Role: Project Manager Responsibility: (To head a team of 18 Engineers)

Coral Hotel Doha (Qatar) 4\*

Feb 2011 – Sept 2011

227 suites

Role: IT Manager (Successful Pre /soft and post opening)

Nuzul Hotel, opened as Park Plaza 4\* Managed by V continents. Oct 2009 – Feb 2011

Role: IT Manager (Successful pre /soft and post opening) 221 suites

Copthorne Hotel Dubai —4\* Managed by Millennium. (DUBAI) Sept 2007 – Oct 2009 Role: IT Specialist. (Successful pre/ Soft and post opening) **188** Rooms/ suites

# **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION**

Diploma in Electronics & Communication Engineering. (D E & C ENGG) From Dr.T.M.A.Pai Polytechnic, Manipal (2000-03)

# **ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS**

- Diploma in Hardware and Networking (Windows 2000 Server and Professional)
- Diploma in Computer Applications MS word, Excel, Access, Powerpoint, Tally & Front page
- Completed a course in Oracle 8i (SQL and Developer 2000)
- Adequate knowledge of C, C++ and Schematics, java and Visual Basics 6.5

### Hobbies

Surf the internet to know the latest developments in the field of technology / science.

### Declaration:-

I hereby declare that the above details of mine are true to the best of my knowledge.

Yours sincerely

## Balaji Shettigar